We are potentially entering World War
and every trader and their mother is
losing money at this very moment. If you
have some type of experience in the
markets, you're probably wondering what
the heck is happening and why are the
markets different. And if you have just
stumbled across trading in 2026, well,
let me tell you something. You did not
pick any better time to begin your
trading journey than today. Because once
you learn how to trade in these chaotic
markets, you can adapt to any type of
markets that you're going to be coming
across in the next couple of months or
the next couple of years. So, let me
break everything down. And as we speak
right now, Q1 of 2026, we have wars
across multiple different regions. We
have oil and gas prices shooting through
the roof and we have political tension
like we've never [music] had before. And
every single week there's a new headline
that feel like it's going to be World
War III. Am I right or am I wrong? Now,
in this video, I'm going to break down
to you exactly how these global events
have impacted the markets in the past,
my thoughts on how this can potentially
affect the market in the near future,
and my personal take and how I
personally trade in this chaos and turn
this massive negative into
[clears throat] a positive in the
markets. So, let's break it down. So, I
want to give you guys some context how
I've personally have experienced both
sides of this type of trading. Very
volatile with loads of fundamentals and
then a very slow moving markets. So, I
stumbled across trading around 2018
when Trump was ending his first term and
I was unprofitable for two consecutive
years until he left the term around the
pandemic towards the ending of it. And
for those two consecutive years, it was
very similar as to what's happening
right now in 2026, where it's a new
headlines every single week, there's a
new battle with a different region, and
the markets are moving very fast and
very sporadic. Now, it was my first time
coming across trading and I didn't
really know what I was doing. So, I was
making a lot of of
entering the moves after they had
already happened, chasing the moves
after they had already happened,
anticipating moves that were never going
to happen. And as soon as Trump left
office and Joe Biden came in for those
next years after the pandemic, I became
a profitable trader. I became a
profitable trader because the patterns
in the markets moved the same every
single time. Joe Biden didn't do
anything in his four years, and there
wasn't major news events, there wasn't
major fundamentals that were driving
price in one direction versus the other.
Everything was moving very slow, and
these patterns were very easy to grab
because Joe Biden really wasn't moving
the market. After Joe Biden left the
presidency and Trump came back in, [__]
hit the fan again. Trump came in
obviously doing major things for the
economy, better things for the world,
keeping the world a better place, and
the markets weren't adapted to that
because we were four years being a
certain way, and now Trump comes in and
changes everything from one day to
another, and that heavily impacts how
people feel about their currency, how
people feel about their 401ks, how
people fear about if they're going to
lose their money, if they if they should
move it around, how countries should
move their money. And this is a lot of
volatility that is brought into the
market for good, but bad if you don't
know how to react to it. Even myself, I
personally myself when Trump did this
new shift into the market, I personally
was negative for about two and a half
months because it takes time for you to
adapt and see the shift in the market
and be able to learn from it. I'm going
to be sharing with you all of these
insights in this video here today. So, I
want to give you context that I've gone
through this before when I was
unprofitable starting my trading
journey. I traded with slow-moving
markets and capitalized off of it, and
then I was impacted as well personally
from this shift from the current
campaign that is being ran around the
world, and I know now how to optimize
it, and I'm going to share it with you
guys. Now, if you've been living under a
rock, you might have missed that right
at the start of the year, Trump abducted
Maduro from Venezuela, taking over the
oil and all the rigs. Trump has gone
into war with Iran and bombing Iran,
Israel, all this war that's happening in
the Middle East, and we have gotten
attacks in Dubai. One of the safest
places in the globe has been attacked by
Iran, its enemy, or by incoming drones
from all over the world. These are
things that if you would have asked
anybody in December of 2025, people
would have said, "No way. Maybe the Iran
situation was predictable." But Dubai
getting bomb bombed, Maduro getting
abducted into the third, fourth day of
the year, never in a million years would
you have expected that. At least not me.
There's no way that I can anticipate for
something like that to happen. So, I
can't be trading anticipating for that
to happen for me to make my decisions in
the markets. I trade for what the market
is giving me [music] in front of me
right now. Now, how the fundamentals
affect what I'm trading with my
technicals, that is what I'm going to
get into in just a second. But you can
never anticipate that Trump is going to
do something like this.
He might come out next week and say that
aliens are real and that he has one at
the White House for all we know. All I
know is that every single move Trump is
doing is for the better of the US
economy. I would never bet against the
dollar. Now, there might be some trades
where I will short-live a
dollar getting weaker, but long-term I
would never short the dollar. There's no
way that Trump would do something to
make the dollar weaker. Just not going
to happen. So, what are we going to do
about this situation? Because we can't
trade scared that Trump is going to come
out with any headlines every single
week. Now, once again, everything that I
believe he's going to be doing is for
the better of this country and I back
Trump every single day. Now, I take that
with a grain of salt because I do need
to trade the markets and I do need to be
able to make a decision around my
technical analysis. Now, I cannot try
and read Trump's mind and be able to
anticipate what is coming next.
Sometimes it will take longer, sometimes
it might not even happen. And other
things might get in between and just
change everything. So, I'm going to give
you the four steps that you need to
follow to be able to optimize these
volatile swings that are happening in
the markets in 2026. This is what I am
doing. This is what it took me some time
to adapt in the markets and it's all for
the better. Volatility is great if you
know how to execute it the right way. If
you don't, you're simply going to miss
out the opportunity in chaos. And when
everything is chaos and everything is
going bad, that's when there's a great
opportunity to get in. And I want to
make something very clear. Just because
I am a profitable trader and I have a
massive community of people that are
profitable alongside with me, we don't
have a magic ball. We don't have a
crystal ball that tells us exactly what
the market is going to do next. As a
profitable trader at the start of this
year, I did not expect for these crazy
swings to happen. And I had a two three
month losing streak. Now, I adapted to
these markets, I learned from my
mistakes, and now is when I am making
profits again from the market. Me being
unprofitable for two months doesn't make
me an unprofitable trader. Just because
I missed two three shots in a basketball
game doesn't mean I'm no longer a good
basketball player. I just simply missed
some shots. Now, I need to adapt to my
game to the type of defensive player
that is up against me. And then from
there, I'm able to learn from my less my
losses. These are lessons and then we
move on forward. So, with that being
said, if you're going through a losing
streak yourself, whether you're an
experienced trader or a new trader in
2026, don't worry. You're trading in
chaotic times. It's not normal for one
president to abduct another president.
It's not normal for wars to happen in
the Middle East in the in the beginning
of the year. It's not normal for the
safest country in the world to get
bombed. Like what the [__] So, don't
beat yourself up if your strategy is not
fully aligned with the markets right
now, and that's simply because the
markets aren't fully aligned with
anything. Now, if you want to learn from
these mistakes and actually be able to
optimize it, just listen to these steps
that I'm going to be breaking down right
now, so you can take advantage from
those traders that took advantage in a
2008 crash. That they saw the problem,
they saw the chaos, they took action,
and then years later they reaped the
reward of it. There's an exact
opportunity happening right now in 2026
with this world crisis. Now, step one,
and I am literally going to sound like
my grandpa. I'm going to sound like the
people talking about the Matrix is
attacking them, and I I hate to sound
this way, and it's very cringey,
but this is going to be the truth.
Step one to optimizing your trading for
2026 is do not listen to the media. Now,
I can't believe I'm saying this because
I hate the whole concept of red pill,
blue pill, the Matrix attack. I don't
believe in that, right? And this is not
that at all. The perfect example that I
can put to this is when Maduro got
arrested and brought to the US, that
happened on a weekend. I remember, I was
stuck in St. Barts. I went to St. Barts
for New Year's, and I was stuck in St.
Barts because Trump closed the airspace
anywhere in the Caribbean, so I couldn't
leave back to Miami.
Couple of days later, he opened up the
airspace, and we came back to the
states. But I remember him getting
abducted on a Friday afternoon or on a
Saturday morning, and all all of my
trader friends, everybody was ready to
full ports and buy as much oil as they
possibly can, anticipating for oil
prices to shoot up when the market
opened on Monday. Market opened on
Monday, and guess what happened?
Nothing. You can see in the screenshot
right here that literally the markets
did not react to it at all. For whatever
reason, the markets didn't react to it.
They just arrested a president of a
country that is heavily influenced by
oil, and that's the main reason why
Trump did that, for the interest of oil
and obviously other crimes that Maduro
did. Now, the market didn't react to
that. So, if everybody was listening to
the media, they would have made a
decision around that, and they could
have potentially gotten burned. Now,
obviously, couple of weeks later, the
war with Iran, Israel, that is what then
ended up shooting prices up on oil, but
you can't directly make a decision based
off of the media. So, don't pay
attention to what the news is saying for
you to make your decision on a specific
trade that you want to take. That is
step number one, and it is so crucial to
do this correctly. Be aware of what is
happening, be informed, but don't let
that make an influence in your decision.
That's it. That's That's the most
important thing. Now, step two is
probably one of the most important
things when it comes to the actual mind
of the trader, when it comes to actual
psychological decision-making behind the
trade, and that is going to be be less
aggressive. Everybody at the start of
the year, they want to meet their goals
at the start of the year. Everybody's
hyped because they want to start off the
year strong, everything that they
studied for during the holidays at the
market is moving slow. Start of the
year, everybody wants to be very
aggressive, do an account flip, pass a
prop firm account, or just make a lot of
money in trading.
And obviously, these global events
heavily affected them. Now, that's fine.
You couldn't expect for something like
that to happen. You just need to adapt
to it. Now, what you do is take a step
back. This is what I personally did
myself. I went from taking three to four
trades a week to taking one trade a
week. And if that trade was not a
perfect trade setup, I simply did not
take it. I can't make a decision on
entering a trade, on having the
fundamentals heavily driving the markets
on something that has never happened
before. My trading is based off of
statistics, it's based off of patterns,
it's based off of recognitions that have
happened in the past that are going to
potentially happen again. And if
something is happening in the world
right now that's very heavily impacting
the markets, something that's never
happened in the past, how can I make a
decision on entering a trade which is
purely based off of statistics and
patterns?
You shouldn't be entering a trade at
all. So, that's why I would stick to one
single trade a week, max two, if you
find a good decision. It's not about
entering every single volatile trade.
It's about entering the right ones.
Quality over quantity is what will keep
you in this game long term. And step two
lays out a perfect for step three. For
me is probably I'd say the backbone of
everything that I'm going to be talking
about this video. And that is that if
you are trying to take a trade at an
all-time high or at an all-time low,
you are not trading, you're gambling.
Traders right now that are buying gold
at 5,000, 6,000, thinking that it's
going to go to 7,000, are simply
gamblers.
Trading is a game of probabilities.
Probabilities because it has happened in
the past. If it's happened in the past
10 times, and out of those 10 times six
of them it went in your favor, this 11th
time there's a 60% chance that it goes
in your favor again. There's data to the
left, there's patterns to the left in
the exact same zone where you are in
right now that they can potentially
reject this resistance or have a
reaction from this support. Now,
if gold is at an all-time high,
how can you anticipate that it's going
to go to the next high? You're just
purely guessing, you're gambling. You
don't have any data that gold will go
from the all-time high of 4,000 to
5,000, or the all-time high of 5,000 to
6,000, or the all-time high from 6,000
to 7,000. You're just wanting to for
price to keep going up based off of the
fundamentals, and that is incorrect. We
are technical traders. We look to the
left, and whatever has happened to the
left, we expect for it to happen again.
Now, you tell me that gold was at 5,000,
it dropped to 4,000, and then you want
to buy from 4,000 up to 5,000. I'll say,
"Okay, it's happened one time in the
past. I guess if that is worth the risk
for you, sure. But, at least you have
some type of data that it's been there
before." So, any traders that are
building strategies right now or
learning how to have these 100% win rate
strategies at these all-time highs are
simply making a big mistake because they
have The data that they're getting from
the trading is what's happening every
single day. There's no years of data.
There's no
market that has been there before for
you to be able to make a logical
decision if this actually makes sense.
It's like right now if we were The
humans were have have gone back and
forth to the moon 100 times. It's very
predictable for us to be able to tell
how long it would take for us to get to
the moon and what's at the moon. Now,
somebody, once we get to the moon, says,
"You know what? It will take us the same
amount of time to get to Mars, and Mars
has the exact same type of planet life
and same distance." That's false. Mars
is a completely different planet, and
there's light-years away to get there.
So, you can't expect for where you are
right now in price to be or take the
exact type of movement to get to this
next spot. A lot more money needs to be
put into the market. It's just so It It
goes a lot deeper than just expecting
for a new high or a a new low. So,
trading at these all-time highs, these
all-time lows is the biggest mistake
that any trader could be making because
there's not enough data to the left.
It's never been there before. There's no
reason why it should have a reaction
from a certain zone if it's only done it
once or twice. That's why I stay away
from these very volatile pairs that
don't have any data to the left. And
this leads me to my next step, which is
something that a lot of traders might
not want to hear.
And that is that you need to know when
it's the right time to get involved into
the markets. A lot of people find out
that oil shot up or that gold shot up or
Bitcoin shot up. And then that's when
they want to get involved. Bitcoin just
hit a 100,000. I want to buy now.
Why would you buy at the all-time high?
Oil just shot up 30%. I want to get
involved right now. Gold is at 5,000. I
want to get involved right now. Why?
You're literally getting involved after
the move has already happened. You need
to know when to get involved in the
volatility. And this is what happens
with a lot of traders. They find out
late and they expect for this volatility
to continue to happen. You capitalize
off of the volatility when you're an
educated trader, when you make your
analysis, you have a decent
understanding of the fundamentals, and
then you capitalize once the volatility
happens, not after the fact. Once the
move is gone, it's gone. You can't
expect for the same jump in price after
it has just happened. And that's what
happens with a lot of traders that are
stumbling across trading in 2026. You've
entered trading in the best possible
time ever in terms of volatility, but
you are entering the trades after the
move has already happened. And you can't
chase these moves down. Once they're
gone, they are gone. Yes, they can have
retracements and they can potentially
have those moves again, but it's never
the same. It's not the first original
move. The first original push is the
best move and that's where the
opportunity is. You need to have your
strategy to be able to identify the
technical analysis and grade your trade
and be able to time the entry correctly.
I can't explain to you how many people
in my DMs come to me after a move has
already happened. They're trying to
figure out how to get in after it has
already gone in the direction.
Once it's gone, it's gone. And you can
expect for it to do that move again. You
simply have to set and forget that trade
and look for that same pattern in a
different market and be able to optimize
it there. So, it's very important for
you to know when and where to apply your
risk. At what point of the volatility
are we in? Has the move already happened
or are we currently setting it up? Now,
look, I'm not just going to sit here and
pretend like I know everything when it
comes to the fundamentals or what
exactly is going to happen in the
market. Again, you can look at the big
institutions. Even them are struggling.
Now, the big difference in between big
institutions and myself and my community
is that we adapt very fast into the
market. We are watching the markets and
their micro moves every single week. And
we have a very clear understanding of
the lower time frame moves along with
the longer time frame fundamentals. A
lot of these big institutions, they're
trading older strategies that are not
up-to-date in 2026. They have these old
strategies that were created in 1990,
2000, even 2008 after the crash. And the
market in 2026 is a completely different
market. Every single week I get on a
call with my students and I break down
the moves for the week that I anticipate
for them to happen. 70%, 80% of the time
I am correct about the direction of the
move. It simply consists of finding the
right entry. What is the specific zone
and what is the specific time to enter?
And most importantly, I review my
traders' trades to make sure that what
they're doing is correct. If you want to
know more about it, click the link in
the description below. If not, hit that
like and subscribe button on this
YouTube channel because we're going to
be dropping more videos like this. And
2026 is only going to bring more
opportunities. If you guys enjoyed this
video, hit a thumbs up and I'll see you
guys in the next one.